## Lydia Brown

# Dubbing Mixer and Dialogue Editor

15 Mansard Close Tring, Hertfordshire, HP23 6DD 07906821151 lydiamaebrown@gmail.com



I am currently employed as a **Dubbing Mixer** at Storm HD. In my position I mix a variety of programs for **broadcast**, therefore I'm very familiar with mixing **R128** but I have also mixed several films for cinema, so I am confident in both stereo and **5.1 surround sound**. Recording voiceover is very much part of my every day, and I have led several **ADR** sessions.

I learned most of my audio and **Pro Tools** skills through my dad who is also a Dubbing Mixer and have been very lucky to build on that knowledge from other mixers I've worked with over the last few years. I thoroughly enjoy working face to face with clients, managing their needs and expectations and have had very good feedback from producers and directors I've worked with.

Recently I have been working as a **Dialogue Editor** on Brassic; an 8 episode Sky Drama. A lot of my background has been in documentary as you'll see from my credits, and this new challenge has pushed me to look for more work within drama, and higher budget documentaries. I am also familiar with **foreign language** editing/mixing since my days at DMS mixing international versions for studios such as Warner and Sony.

## Industry Employment

Storm HD/ Dubbing Mixer

JUL 2018- PRESENT, LONDON

**Digital Media Services /** Dubbing Mixer

SEP 2016 - JUL 2018, LONDON

**Digital Media Services /** Technical Production Assistant

JUN 2016 - SEP 2016, LONDON

### **Education**

The Jump Digital School

Full Stack Coding Bootcamp JAN 2021-JULY 2021, LONDON

The Arts University Bournemouth (Bournemouth Film School) BA Film Production-

Specialising in Sound and Editing

SEP 2013 - JUN 2016, BOURNEMOUTH

**Avid Media Composer Editing/Effects Essentials** 

Avid MC 101/110

JAN 2015, BOURNEMOUTH

#### Software

**Avid Pro Tools**, Microsoft Office, **Izotope RX**, Sound Minor, **Source Connect**, IOS. (Control surfaces I currently use are **D-command** and **Icon**, am also familiar with Avid Artist Mix and Faderports)

Program Title	Broadcaster	Genre	Year
BRASSIC	Sky One	Drama	2021
FIFA 22	EA Games	Video Game	2021
FIFA 21	EA Games	Video Game	2020
Sue Perkins: Along the US Mexico Border	BBC1	Documentary Series	2020
Money Bags Pilot	None	Factual Entertainment	2020
Then and Now Pilot	None	Documentary Series	2020
Royal Opera House – Various Shorts	Cinema Release	Performing Arts	2018-2020
Making of: Marc Marquez	DAZN	Documentary Series	2020
In Other words	Art Agency Partners	Podcast	2018-2020
The Disordered Eye	BBC 2	Documentary	2020
Pilgrimage: Road to Istanbul	BBC2	Factual Entertainment Series	2020
Secrets of the Solar System	UKTV	Documentary Series	2020
The Edge Cast	The Edge Picture Co.	Podcast	2020
Buried Secrets of WWII	History	Documentary Series	2019
The Trans Women Athlete Dispute with Martina Navratilova	BBC 1	Documentary	2019
Becoming Matisse	BBC 2	Documentary	2019
David Harewood: Psychosis and Me	BBC 2	Documentary	2019
Craft Party	CBeebies	Children's Entertainment	2019
Al Murray's Great British Pub Quiz	Discovery/ Quest	Factual Entertainment	2019
A Royal Team Talk: Tackling Mental Health	BBC 1	Documentary	2019
lt's Grime Up North	Channel 4	Documentary Series	2019
FIFA 20	EA Games	Video Game	2019
When Double Acts Fall Out	Channel 5	Documentary	2019
Celebrity Painting Challenge	BBC 1	Factual Entertainment Series	2019
Ken Dodd: How Tickled We Were	Channel 5	Documentary	2019
Pilgrimage: Road to Rome	BBC 2	Factual Entertainment Series	2019
Lazy Boy Flippers	UKTV	Factual Entertainment Series	2019
Armchair Britain	BBC2	Documentary Series	2019
Outrageous Acts of Science	Discovery	Factual Entertainment Series	2018
FIFA 19	EA Games	Video Game	2018